You've read the ad, now see the movie!
The Naked Gun: From the Files of Police Squad! is a
comedy, crime film directed by David Zucker.
When the bumbling Lieutenant Frank Drebin investigates events following the shooting of
his partner, he stumbles upon an attempt to assassinate Queen Elizabeth II.
Frank Drebin, played by Leslie Nielsen.
Jane Spencer, played by Priscilla Presley.
Vincent Ludwig, played by Ricardo Montalban.
Ed Hocken, played by George Kennedy.
Nordberg, played by O. J. Simpson.
Mrs. Nordberg, played by Susan Beaubian.
The Naked Gun: From the Files of Police Squad!
is a 1988 American crime comedy film directed by David Zucker,
and produced and released by Paramount Pictures.
The film stars Leslie Nielsen as the bumbling police lieutenant Frank Drebin.
The film features fast-paced slapstick comedy, including
many visual and verbal puns and gags.
The film is based on the character portrayed by Nielsen in the television
series Police Squad!, and is also a continuation of the latter.
The core creative team behind Police Squad!
and the film series includes the team of David Zucker, Jim Abrahams, and
Jerry Zucker (ZAZ) as well as Pat Proft in varying combinations.
Released on December 2, 1988, The Naked Gun was a critical and commercial success, which led to two
sequels: The Naked Gun 2½: The Smell of Fear (1991) and Naked Gun 33⅓: The Final Insult (1994).
It is now considered one of the greatest comedy films of all time.
A fourth film, a legacy sequel directed and co-written by Akiva Schaffer and
starring Liam Neeson and Pamela Anderson, was released in 2025.
The film explores themes of assassination, police, aquarium, baseball, parody.
The tone is lighthearted.